command his family here with one of the
best and the brightest, Mr. Doug
Williams in the building. And we are
here at the H.B.CU combine, but also the
IP Pro Day. What you doing here watching
this? Cuz you could be out having time
off right now. You could be enjoying
yourself on vacation, but you chose to
be here, represent yourself. Why is
that?
>> Well, this is my time off. That's what
it's all about. No, this is a great
opportunity for guys from H.B.CU and IP,
the guys international to come in the
bun and join with the H.B.CU CU to show
what they capable of doing, you know,
and I take my hat off to the NFL for
putting this on, you know, give us an
opportunity to bring guys from H.B.CU in
who don't get an opportunity to go to
the combine. And a lot of scouts don't
go to their school for proday. So now
you you don't go to their school, so we
bring you up here. We try to get the the
big the best and the brightest kids with
with the ability to maybe make it to the
next level. So we bring them up here.
It's about 50 kids from H.B.CU cus along
with about 11 guys from IP and had this
showcase which is I think is great
>> and this was not something that existed
back when you were coming out of an
HB.CU right talk about the growth of
HB.CU's CU's and showcasing this talent
because again back when you played you
didn't have a chance to showcase your
talent.
>> Well the good thing about when I played
guys we didn't have to cuz the scouts
found you. Back then it was a lot of
guys from HB.CU who got an opportunity
to go to the NFL. Now that is not
happening. So with this showcase, it
gives these guys an opportunity to be
seen by scouts who might go back and
tell their team uh people who running
their draft and things like that that we
got this kid, this kid showed out and or
what have you and get an opportunity to
play in the league. And I think that's
what it's all about to get more kids
from H.B.CU an opportunity to play in
the National Football League.
>> Mr. Doug, it's so surprising to me to
hear that back in the day it was better
that back in the day you guys had more
opportunities cuz you very seldom hear
about degression when we go forward,
right? And it seems like there was a
degression in essence.
>> Well, let let me tell you a scenario
that make you understand what I'm
talking about. When I came out as a
freshman, uh there was a guy in Jackson
State by the name of Walter Peyton,
Robert Bazil, Jackie Slater, all on the
same team in Jackson. All those guys was
first round picks back in the day after
H.B.CU. They said, "I had a guy named
Gary Big Hand Johnson, Robert Barber,
myself, James Hunter. We was all first
round pick at Gramlin back in the day."
Well, that's not happening anymore
because now kids got an opportunity to
go to school that wasn't allowing them
to play at their school back in the day.
So therefore, the kind of talent kind of
dwindled away from the H.B.CU and went
to other institution. But that don't
mean the H.B.CU don't have talent. And
that's what we doing this for to let
them know that we got some guys that
deserve an opportunity to play in the
National Football League.
>> And not every NFL team does this, right?
But a team that you love, the Burgundy
and Gold, Washington, they have decided
to hold this combine, hold this showcase
again, not only for international
players, but also for HB.CU alumni and
people trying to get to the NFL. How
much pride do you take in that knowing
that an organization that you bled for,
that you came to and won a Super Bowl,
is doing this and taking the time to
show love to these players?
>> Well, first of all, let me say this. The
NFL contacted uh Adam Peters, our
general manager, about hosting the
showcase here at at our facility. And
Adam and Dan was, "Hey, whatever we can
do." And that's an opportunity for them
to come here and host it right here. I
can walk across across the street, I
guess, in my office and come out here to
this. I thought I take my hat off to
Adam for doing this. Take my hat off to
the NFL for allowing this to happen in
our facility. So, this is a great
opportunity. And it's not just players
that come to the NFL and find success.
It's coaches as well. And you know that
better than anybody with your son being
a former HB.CU coach. Now he's in the
building. I haven't really got to talk
to you since we hired your son. And what
has that been like being able to just
share all this with him?
>> Man, look, it's such a great great
opportunity for me just to be able to
know coming to work every day down the
hall is my son. Wow.
>> You know, and the good part good news
about that, I had another kid that I
that I recruited when I was at Gramlin
that played for me when I was at
Gramlin. He just got hired by the
Seattle Seahawks. He was a quarterback,
too. So, I was talking to DJ. I said,
"Man, could you imagine you and Jonathan
who played together are now in
quarterback rooms and two NFL teams?" I
think that is big. But for me, I don't
think it's anything bigger than me
sitting in my office and my son coming
knock on my door.
>> But if it wasn't for the things you did
on the field and off the field, they
might not get this opportunity. This
might not be a thing. These players
might not get to showcase themselves.
So, of course, Mr. Doug, I got to tell
you, thank you. Thank you for being a
trailblazer. It's not easy being one of
the first to do things and you did that,
sir. So, we appreciate you, man.
>> Well, let me say that. James Harris,
Shaq Harris, who's kind of like close to
me, kind of like a brother. We the one
who came up with the the Legacy Bowl and
Black College Football Hall of Fame and
all this was born from them.
>> And I take my head off to Shaq and
myself for doing this. Guys like Mel
Blunt who Art Shell, we all is a big
group. And and and the reason why we do
that is because of where we come from,
H.B.CU. And if we didn't do it, we who's
going to do it? So, we had to at least
do something and hope that the younger
guys that's coming up behind us would
take this and keep it going forward.
>> And Mr. Doug, you have name dropped some
heavy names, some heavy NFL legends
there, all coming from H.B.CU. And I
talked to the guys on command center a
few weeks ago about the misconception
about players, these young men going to
H.B.CU and not getting a chance in the
NFL. There is a misconception there that
if you go to HB.CU, you might not get
that chance. Explain why that is not
true. Well, you know, our running back
here, Bill, our running back, you know,
he started at at Alabama State and and
played most of his ball at Alabama
State. Let you know there are some
players that's at H.B.CU that can play
in this league if given the opportunity.
And I think what has to happen and I
think our scout does a good job. I think
the scouts around the league when they
go out and watch these player, don't
grade the school, grade the player.
>> I think that's the biggest mistake
that's made.
>> Well, Mr. Doug, we appreciate you again.
Thank you for being a trailblazer. Thank
you for allowing things like this to
happen, my brother, the man, his family.
We are here with one of the best to ever
do it. Doug Williams, appreciate your
time.